Himat Shah

+358 465840099 himat@cs.uef.fi Kauppakatu 39 c, 38 80100, Joensuu, Finland



PAGE 1 - APPLICATION

About me

It is my passion to learn about computer science, machine learning, data science, and web mining. Having been a programmer since I was a teenager, I possess solid programming skills and knowledge. I strive to be a lifelong learner who pays attention to details. Since machine learning can benefit many people, it is my main motivation.

I'm 38-year-old PhD in computer science machine learning, who has studied and worked for the latest ~6 years in different positions on IT and software industry. My career started from software development and moved from there to more of a teaching and training side.

Latest 3-5 years (or so) I've been studying as a PhD computer science in Finland and graduated in November 2022. My research group is in Joensuu city at school of computing university of Eastern Finland Joensuu. My research group name is machine learning, and my research field is data science, web content mining where I have developed 4 different methods keyword extraction both language dependent and independent.

I love programming and spending most of my spare time practicing and improving my programing skills. I'm good at getting the big picture to dig deeper in just the right spots. I love to prove before doing so that correct things are built and then build them. And I'm hungry for more. I love interacting with customers and provide value to their needs. I love constant learning and complex environments where you face challenges on multiple levels.

What I am looking for reputable company in Finland where I can utilize my skills and knowledge which I gain spending lots of time in it.

Himat Shah

+358 465840099 himat@cs.uef.fi Kauppakatu 39 c, 38 80100, Joensuu, Finland



PAGE 2 - CV

Experience

Database Programmer Central Hospital Joensuu (SiunSote), Finland 9/2020 – 12/2021 1.5 years

Job Description

- Task to write especial queries with complex joins.
- Retrieve patient's records for research purposes.
- SQL server, Qlik, SQL, PowerBi, MongoDB.
- Backup and maintain databases.
- Different database used Datawarehouse.

Assistant Professor Engineering University (QUEST), Pakistan 4/2014 – 1/2018 3.7 years

Job Description

- Overall responsibilities for the university web development and teaching.
- Responsible for the motivation and development of 10 member staff.
- Lab work and lab assignments.
- In Information technology.

Oracle Trainer SZABIST Nawabshah, Pakistan 4/2014 – 4/2016 2 years

Job Description

- Training Oracle to Student in the evening time
- Extra job in the evening after university time.
- Designing, installing, upgrading, patching, tuning, monitoring, and troubleshooting databases.

Oracle Trainer SZABIST Hyderabad, Pakistan 4/2012 – 4/2014 2 years

Job Description

- Overall responsibilities for teaching.
- Government trainings for the students in Oracle 10g.
- DBA oracle training for certifications.
- Designing, installing, upgrading, patching, tuning, monitoring, and troubleshooting databases.

Important Links

GitHub https://github.com/adeelshah110

LinkedIn Https://linkedin.com/in/himatshah110

Webpage http://cs.uef.fi/~himat/

Google Scholar https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=UhLUHdcAAAAJ&hl=en

Research Gate https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Himat-Shah

Certification

Oracle 10 g (DBA)

OCP

2012

Machine Learning

Online Keyword Extraction for Webpages machine learning tools

- http://cs.uef.fi/~himat/Hrank
- http://cs.uef.fi/~himat/Drank
- http://cs.uef.fi/~himat/WebRank
- http://cs.uef.fi/~himat/ACI2

Research Interest

- Keyword extraction for webpages
- Machine learning
- Topic modeling
- Webpage summarization
- Title extraction

IT Trainings

- **Is Programming for me?** TE-Office Riviera School Joensuu 13.2.2023—24.01.2024

Language	Months	Level	Status	
Python	2.2	Advance	Completed	
HTML, CSS	1.0	Very good	Completed	
JavaScript	1.1	Very good	Completed	
PowerBi	0.6	Good	Going On	
React	0.4	started	Going on	
React	0.2	Good	Going on	

Education				
2018-2022	PhD	Computer Science	School of Computing University of Eastern Finland.	
2014-2016	Masters	Information Technology	Engineering University (QUEST), Pakistan.	
2010-2013	Masters	MBA	University of Wales Cardiff, United Kingdom.	
2010-2010	Diploma	PGD Level -7	City college of London (CLC), United Kingdom.	
2004-2008	Bachelors	Computer Science	University of Sindh Jamshoro, Pakistan.	

Publication

Journal Papers

- I. H. Shah, P. Fränti, "Combining statistical, structural, and linguistic features for keyword extraction from web pages", In journal of Applied Computing and Intelligence, Aims press publication, 2022.
- II. M. Shah, H. Pathan, H. Shah, and W. Shah," Effects of SMS texting on academic writing skills of undergraduate students at a public sector university in Pakistan", In Journal of Literature, Languages and Linguistics, 2021.
- III. A. Khan, A. Burdi, S. Awan, H. Shah, "Image segmentation approach using python OpenCV to detect tuberculosis", University of Sindh journal, 2019.
- IV. Laghari, H. He, S. Karim, H. Shah, and K. Karn, "Quality of Experience Assessment of Video Quality in Social Clouds", Wireless Communications and Mobile, 2017.

Conference Papers

- I. H. Shah, R. Mariescu-Istodor, P. Fränti, "WebRank: Language-Independent Extraction of Keywords from Webpages", In IEEE International Conference on Progress in Informatics and Computing (PIC), IEEE, 2021.
- II. H. Shah, M. Rezaei, and P. Fränti, DOM-based keyword extraction from webpages," In proceedings of international conference on artificial intelligence, information processing and cloud computing (AIIPCC), Sanya, China, Article No. 62, 2019.
- III. H. Shah, M. U. S. Khan, and P. Fränti, "Hrank: A keywords extraction method from web pages using POS tags," In IEEE International Conference on Industrial Informatics (INDIN), Helsinki, 2019.

Other Skills

- Very strong design skills.
- Languages: Sindhi (native), English (excellent), Finnish (B1), Germany and Russian (beginner),
 Chinese (Ni hao!).
- Personality: analytical, creative, goal-oriented, determined, good sense of humor.
- Always keep promises and complete the projects started.

Hobbies

- Running, badminton, football, floorball, orienteering, marathons, ice swimming, F1 (driving in dreams), travelling.
- Cricket, music, volunteer works, socialize, event creator, making friends, cooking.

References

Professor Pasi Fränti,
 School of Computing, University of Eastern Finland
 Office: +358 (0)50 442 2265

E-mail: first.last@uef.fi